<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
  <p>
    <code>input/pagecontent/index.xml</code>
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>This guide is not complete - most of the discursive sections have only placeholders while the
      technical content is being developed</b>
  </p>
    <a name="overview"> </a>
  <h3>Technical Overview</h3>
  <p>Additional detail/context setting for those who have significant background in the domain. (Try
    to make as understandable as you can, but set important context).</p>
  <p>The main sections of this IG are:</p>
  <p>This home page which sets out basic introduction and background</p>
  <p>The following sections under Guidance that provide detail explanation and guidance:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Use Cases and Work Flows - describes intended uses of a digital protocol that follows this
      specification.</li>
    <li>Information Models - The structure of Protocol information seen from different viewpoints</li>
    <li>Mappings - Guidance converting the sections of a protocol into FHIR</li>

  </ul>
  <p>Artifacts - The technical components (Profiles, Extensions, Value Sets etc) of the
    Implementation Guide</p>

      <a name="objectives"> </a>
  <h3>Core Objectives </h3>
  <p>The Vulcan HL7 FHIR Accelerator aims to bridge research and clinical care through use of FHIR,
    strategically connecting collaborators to maximize expertise and efforts. The Vulcan Utilizing
    the Digital Protocol (UDP) project enhances the integration of clinical and translational
    research with clinical care by enabling digital protocol exchange through FHIR, supporting
    Vulcan's mission to connect these domains and research integration into care.</p>
  <p>This Implementation Guide (IG) allows for FHIR-based exchange of digital clinical trial
    protocols aligned to ICH M11 (Clinical electronic Structured Harmonized Protocols, or CeSHarP)
    in a manner compatible across clinical research stakeholders. The specific initial use case
    address within is exchange between sponsors and regulators, while building foundations for, and
    avoiding blockers to, additional use cases that benefit the multiple stakeholders who utilize
    protocol information</p>
  <h3>Scope</h3>
  <p>The Vulcan UDP project supports Vulcan's mission to connect clinical and translational research
    to clinical care by enabling digital protocol exchange through FHIR. The main goal of this FHIR
    Implementation Guide is to concentrate on near-term achievable use cases to ensure immediate
    impact and feasibility, while building foundations for, and avoiding blockers to, long-term
    cross-stakeholder compatibility across many additional use cases. Governance requirements
    include retaining alignment with ICH M11 and compatible standards of CDISC USDM and Controlled
    Terminology as well as related uses of FHIR such as those in the <a
      href='https://hl7.org/fhir/uv/ebm/history.html'>Evidence Based Medicine </a> (EBM)
    Implementation Guide. </p>
  <p>
    <strong>In Scope</strong>
  </p>
  <p>The initial use case focuses on <strong>sponsor-to-regulator exchange of protocols which align
    to ICH M11</strong>, leveraging and enabling compatibility with related standards where
    possible, and building cross-organization relationships to enable future governance. </p>
  <p>
    <strong>Out of scope</strong>
  </p>
  <p>While out of scope for this version of the Implementation Guide, the future aim is to develop a
    use case roadmap, considering the broad spectrum of potential use cases of digital protocols and
    seeking opportunities to establish foundational connections. (See also the Use Cases &amp;
    Workflows section). </p>
  <p>Detailed governance processes are also out of scope for this version but will be addressed in
    future iterations. Successful governance will require active participation in HL7 processes to
    ensure long-term alignment with related efforts such as EBM, and with other organizations, such
    as ICH M11, CDISC, and TransCelerate.</p>


<h3>Structure of this Implementation Guide</h3>
<p>This FHIR Implementation Guide is organized across the following tabs:</p>
<p>-     <strong>Home</strong>: Provides an orientation outlining objectives, background, and scope</p>
<p>-     <strong>Guidance:</strong> Describes how the technical work was approached and why certain decisions were made</p>
<p>-     <strong>Use Cases &amp; Workflows:</strong> Provides a view to use cases covered in this Implementation Guide as well as those others are working on and future potential use cases across stakeholders </p>
<p>-     <strong>Implementation Best Practice:</strong> Provides considerations for how to leverage this Implementation Guide</p>
<p>There is also a comprehensive <strong>Table of Contents</strong> to aid navigation across all content. </p>

</div>
=======
  <ul>
    <li>This home page which sets out basic introduction and background </li>
    <li>The following sections under <a href="guidance.html">Guidance</a> that provide detail explanation and guidance: 
      <ul>
      <li><a href="useCases.html">Use Cases and Work Flows</a> - describes intended uses of a digital
      protocol that follows this specification. </li>
      <li><a href="infoModels.html">Information Models</a> - The structure of Protocol information
      seen from different viewpoints </li>
      <li><a href="mappings.html">Mappings</a> - Guidance converting the sections of a protocol into
      FHIR </li>
      </ul>
    </li>
  <li><a href="artifacts.html">Artifacts</a> - The technical components (Profiles, Extensions, Value
    Sets etc) of the Implementation Guide </li>
  <!--    <li>
      <a href="downloads.html">Downloads</a> - Allows downloading a copy of this implementation guide and
    other useful information
    </li> -->
  </ul>
</div>
