<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>

  <blockquote>
    <p><img src="icon-warning.png" alt="Take note:" /></p>
  <p>
    <b>This IG has some content outstanding in the Information Models section and the Use cases section, 
      and additional section under the Audience Specific section of Implementation Best Practice"</b>
  </p>
  </blockquote>

  <a name="overview"> </a>
  <h3>Technical Overview</h3>
  <p>This guide describes the representation of a Study Protocol in FHIR format.  The Document focus of protocol 
    organization is provided by the ICH M11 CeSHarP Template and Technical Guide.  For a more structured approach 
    to the data there is the CDISC USDM model. Both are represented in the FHIR Representation mapping spreadsheet, 
    but for this version of the iG the emphasis is on the M11 approach.</p>

  <p>The key FHIR resources used are ResearchStudy and Composition and we also draw on some profiles and extension from the EBM IG.</p>

  <p>For more description of the releationship between the resources, extensions and profiles see the FHIR Representation section and 
    the actual specifications in the Artifacts section</p>

      <a name="objectives"> </a>
  <h3>Core Objectives </h3>
  <p>The Vulcan HL7 FHIR Accelerator aims to bridge research and clinical care through use of FHIR,
    strategically connecting collaborators to maximize expertise and efforts. The Vulcan Utilizing
    the Digital Protocol (UDP) project enhances the integration of clinical and translational
    research with clinical care by enabling digital protocol exchange through FHIR, supporting
    Vulcan's mission to connect these domains and research integration into care.</p>
  <p>This Implementation Guide (IG) allows for FHIR-based exchange of digital clinical trial
    protocols aligned to ICH M11 (Clinical electronic Structured Harmonized Protocols, or CeSHarP)
    in a manner compatible across clinical research stakeholders. The specific initial use case
    address within is exchange between sponsors and regulators, while building foundations for, and
    avoiding blockers to, additional use cases that benefit the multiple stakeholders who utilize
    protocol information.</p>

      <a name="scope"> </a>
  <h3>Scope </h3>
  <p>The Vulcan UDP project enables digital protocol exchange through FHIR, supporting Vulcan's
    mission to connect clinical and translational research to clinical care. The main goal of this
    FHIR Implementation Guide is to concentrate on near-term achievable use cases to ensure
    immediate impact and feasibility, while building foundations for, and avoiding blockers to,
    long-term cross-stakeholder compatibility across many additional use cases. Governance
    requirements include retaining alignment with ICH M11 and compatible standards of CDISC USDM and
    Controlled Terminology as well as related uses of FHIR such as those in the 
    <a href="https://hl7.org/fhir/uv/ebm/history.html" > Evidence Based Medicine (EBM) </a> Implementation Guide.</p>
  <p>
    <strong>In Scope</strong>
  </p>
  <p>The initial use case focuses on <strong>sponsor-to-regulator exchange of protocols which align
    to ICH M11</strong>, leveraging and enabling compatibility with related standards where
    possible, and building cross-organization relationships to enable future governance. </p>
  <p>
    <strong>Out of scope</strong>
  </p>
  <p>While out of scope for this version of the Implementation Guide, the future aim is to develop a
    use case roadmap, considering the broad spectrum of potential use cases of digital protocols and
    seeking opportunities to establish foundational connections. (See also the Use Cases and Workflows section). </p>
  <p>Detailed governance processes are also out of scope for this version but will be addressed in
    future iterations. Successful governance will require active participation in HL7 processes to
    ensure long-term alignment with related efforts such as EBM, and with other organizations, such
    as ICH M11, CDISC, and TransCelerate.</p>


      <a name="structure"> </a>
<h3>Structure of this Implementation Guide</h3>
<p>This FHIR Implementation Guide is organized across the following tabs:</p>

<ul>
  <p><strong>IG Home</strong>: Provides an orientation outlining objectives, background, and scope</p>
  <ul>
    <p>Home: This home page</p>
    <p>Background: Placing this work in the wider context</p>
    <p>Implementation Best Practice: Provides some general pointers on implementation, and also picks out key points from differ3ent audience prespectives.</p>
  </ul>
  <p><strong>Guidance:</strong> Describes how the technical work was approached and why certain decisions were made</p>
  <ul>
    <p>Use Cases and Workflows: Provides a view to use cases covered in this Implementation Guide as well as those others are working on and future potential use cases across stakeholders </p>
    <p>Protocol Preparation: A guide to preparation of a protocol for submission according to the M11 format</p>
    <p>Information Models: Explains how the USDM, M11 and FHIR models are related</p>
    <p>FHIR Representation: Shows how elements of the protocol are represented in FHIR.  Also provides a link to a mapping spreadsheet.</p>
    <p>Bundles: Discusses representation of protocol sections within FHIR bundles and the operational consequences</p>
  </ul>
  <p><strong>Artifact Index:</strong> Lists the formal specification of the extensions, profiles, terminology and examples.</p>
</ul>
</div>